To summarise: Prudence and Belisaire Beresford are married,..
总结一下:谨慎与天才 贝雷斯福德结婚了..
..they have one daughter,..
..他们有一个女儿，..
..two adorable grandchildren,..
..两个可爱的孙子，..
..and they will live happily ever after.
..他们会幸福地生活 从此以后。
Things have not turned out the way I expected !
事情还没有结果 我期望的方式！
Very profound, but hardly new.
非常深刻，但并非新鲜事物。
I am bored. I am so very bored.
好无聊。 我好无聊。
I am in a deep, dark vault.
我在一个深沉的黑暗穹顶中。
You have buried me alive.
你把我活埋了。
When they open my coffin,..
当他们打开我的棺材时，..
..they will see the scratches on the lid..
..他们会看到划痕 在盖子上..
where I wore my fingers down to stumps..
我把手指放在哪里 到树桩上
..fighting to get out. - What's the matter with you ?
..战斗出去。 -你怎么了？
Oh, nothing ! Nothing happens, that's all.
哦，什么都没有！ 什么都没发生，仅此而已。
I can't take any more of this humdrum existence.
我不能再忍受了 这种单调乏味的存在。
And I suppose you are fully content ?
我想你是 完全满足？
Colonel Beresford,..
贝雷斯福德上校.. 18岁
..former head of the Secret Service,..
..前负责人 特勤局
..man of mystery, of missions impossible...
..神秘的人， 不可能完成的任务...
Don't you ache anymore for excitement ?
你不疼了吗 兴奋吗？
For romantic adventure ?
为了浪漫的冒险？
Imagine the thrill..
想象一下激动。
..of hearing a knock at the door, to go to open it..
..听到敲门声， 去打开它..
..and see a dead man stagger in !
..看到一个死人交错进来！
If he was dead, he wouldn't be staggering.
如果他死了，他不会 令人st目结舌。
But yes, they always stagger before they die.
但是是的，他们总是错开 在他们死之前
Then they fall - uttering enigmatic words, like :..
然后他们跌倒了 莫名其妙的单词，如:..
..''The Spotted Leopard... Argh... !''
斑点豹子... 啊...！''
I don't think I like dead men who stagger about.
我不认为我喜欢死人 谁错了。
Oh, that'll be Meals on Wheels !
哦，那将是在车轮上用餐！
What are you doing ?
你在做什么 ？
Can you smell something ?
你能闻到些什么吗？
< No, nothing.
<不，没有。
Can't you smell that odour ?
你闻不到那种气味吗？
< An odour - of what ? - Of... I'm not sure...
<有什么气味？ -不确定...
Of old age.
晚年。
< Old age ? - Yes, exactly that. Old age.
<老年？ -是的。老年。
Thank you very much. -< No - no...
非常感谢你。 -<不-不...
It isn't you, it's me.
不是你，是我。
For some time, I've felt old age creeping up on me.
有一段时间了，我已经老了 爬到我身上。
Me, I feel nothing.
我，我什么都没有。
You feel nothing. One feels nothing. -< When you've quite finished..
你什么都没有没有任何感觉。 -<完成后..
..conjugating the verb "to feel"... -< But we're not old !
..使动词“感觉”结合起来... -<但是我们不老！
Not old ?  Aren't we pensioners ?
不老 ？我们不是退休人员吗？
When you retired, it ruined my life.
当您退休时，它毁了 我的生活。
It was you who wanted a vacation. - To take holidays - precisely.
是您想休假。 -要放假-恰到好处。
Anyway, don't take any notice of me.
无论如何， 别理我
How are things, George ?
乔治怎么样？
I'm burning the dead leaves. Anything else?
我正在燃烧枯叶。 还要别的吗？
That's fine.
没关系。
I don't believe I've seen you like this before.
我不相信我已经看过 你以前喜欢这样
It's been churning around in my mind for a long time.
一直在搅拌 在我心中很长一段时间。
Why not buy a new hat ? - I already have lots !
为什么不买新帽子呢？ -我已经有很多！
So what if you have 40,..
那如果你有40点呢
..another might do the trick. Let's go.
..另一个可能会成功。 我们走吧。
I have 44; and the hats all resemble each other.
我有44个；和所有的帽子 彼此相似。
Even though there are subtle differences between them.
即使有微妙之处 他们之间的差异。
I would love something exciting to happen to us.
我会喜欢的东西 激动发生在我们身上。
It would us both good.
这对我们俩都很好。
If only a fairy-godmother would appear...
如果只是仙女 会出现...
Conductor...
导体...
What is wrong ?
怎么了 ？
A woman was being strangled in the train that overtook us.
一个女人被勒死 在超越我们的火车上。
I saw it all.
我都看了 65岁
Tell me calmly exactly what you saw.
完全冷静地告诉我 你看到了什么
I was asleep...
我睡着了...
The other train overtook us...
另一列火车超越了我们。
And I saw the back of a man - strangling a woman.
我看到一个男人的后背 -勒死一个女人。
Strangling a woman ? - Yes.
勒死一个女人？ -是的
Like in the book you are reading ?
就像书中一样 您正在阅读 ？
Exactly the same !
一模一样 ！
Well, then...
好吧...
Rudi, did you see anything strange on the 4:50 express ?
鲁迪，你看到什么了吗 4:50快递有异样吗？
No, why ?
没有为什么 ？
Nothing, forget it.
没事，算了。
I would like to know what you intend to do.
我想知道 你打算做。
I am not a policeman. But, if it will reassure you,..
我不是警察。 但是，如果它能让您放心，..
..I will make out an incident report.
..我会找出来 事件报告。
An incident ?
有事吗
It was a crime !
这是犯罪！
Aunt Babette !
巴贝特姨妈！
Prudence, I have been witness to a crime !
谨慎一点 我见证了犯罪！
A crime ? - Yes, a crime !
犯罪？ -是的，犯罪！
No, no, not a thing !
不，不，不是东西！
No mention of a corpse.
没有提到尸体。
You don't believe I invented it ? - Of course not !
你不相信我发明了它吗？ - 当然不是 ！
You make me feel better.
你让我感觉更好。
That conductor, he didn't believe me.
那个指挥 他不相信我。
But I gave him a clear statement of what I saw.
但是我给他一个清晰的 我所看到的陈述。
An ordinary attacker would have fled..
普通攻击者 会逃跑..
..and left the body.
..并离开了身体。
So, it was premeditated, or a crime of passion...
因此，它是有预谋的， 或激情犯罪...
Jealousy, anger - and the man strangles...
嫉妒，愤怒-和那个男人 勒死...
But I don't see what he did with the body.
但是我看不到 他对身体做了什么。
Ah ! He threw it from the window.
啊！他把它从窗户扔了。
He hid it in a suitcase.
他把它藏在手提箱里。
What sort of killer walks around with a body in a suitcase ?
什么样的杀手四处走动 放在手提箱里的尸体？
It would be noticed.
这将被注意到。
One more, for the road ?
再来一条路？
As far as I'm concerned, he threw it from the window.
就我而言 他把它从窗户扔了。
< Or the corpse staggered off !
<或尸体错开！
Your assassin was burly ? -< Yes.
你的刺客很魁梧？ -<是的。
< At least it seemed so to me.
<至少对我来说是如此。
< Big enough, mainly brown.
<足够大，主要是棕色。
I only saw his back.
我只看到他的背影。
And the unfortunate victim, so. Argh !
和不幸的受害者一样。 啊！
She wore red gloves !
她戴着红色手套！
< It... was horrible. -< You must have..
<这...太可怕了。 -<你一定有..
..dreamt it, or witnessed a domestic dispute..
..做梦，或目击 国内纠纷
..less tragic than you imagined.
..比您想象的要悲惨。
Less tragic ?! It was a crime ! I saw it with my own eyes.
少悲惨？！这是犯罪！ 我亲眼看到了它。
< I am disappointed ! Your Belisaire is..
<我很失望！ 您的Belisaire是..
..like the rest of them. He doesn't believe me.
..像其他人一样。 他不相信我。
And this happened somewhere beyond Andelieux ?
这发生在某处 超越Andelieux？
Yes.
是。
I remember the place. There was a curve..
我记得那个地方。 有一条曲线..
..that rocked me in my seat.
..那使我震惊。
And our train went through the station at Andelieux..
我们的火车经过了 Andelieux的车站
..ten minutes later. There you are, Belisaire !
十分钟后。 Belisaire，您到了！
< I shall need absolute peace of mind..
<我需要绝对 内心的平静..
..during my trip abroad.
..我在国外旅行期间。
< Where are you going to hunt, this time ?  - In Guiana.
<您要去哪里狩猎， 这次 ？ -在圭亚那。
The Zigoeunus Thomasus moth. The male.
Zigoeunus Thomasus 蛾。男性 这是最优雅的飞蛾 在亚马逊地区...
< Why are you ironing your kilt ?
<为什么要熨烫苏格兰短裙？
For my reunion in Glasgow.
我在格拉斯哥的聚会。
You know, the Society of the Oval Thistle.
你知道吗， 椭圆蓟。
Have you forgotten I'm leaving the day after tomorrow ?
你忘了我要走吗 后天？
Then you must devote yourself to ironing your pleats.
那你就必须全身心投入 熨烫褶皱。
What are you doing ?
你在做什么 ？
Drop this nonsense of Aunt Babette's ''crime'' !
废话 巴贝特姨妈的“罪行”！
You've forgotten that crime is our business.
你忘了 犯罪是我们的责任。
It is obvious that your aunt was mistaken.
很明显你阿姨 弄错了
Commissioner Richard searched everywhere.
理查德专员 到处搜寻。
Trains, stations, hospitals, morgues. No sign of a body.
火车，车站，医院， 太平间。没有身体的迹象。
No-one reported missing.
没有人报告失踪。
The train that overtook..
超车的火车..
..Babette's must have been the 4:50..
..贝贝特一定是 4:50
..that stops at Aigrefonds.
..在Aigrefonds停下。
Then, the railway track..
然后，铁路轨道
..follows the county boundary for some distance...
..跟随县境 一段距离...
But then, there actually is a curve.
但是之后， 实际上有一条曲线。
And then ?
然后 ？
The assassin threw the body out the window.
刺客扔了 窗外的身体。
< Frankly, that's what you want to have happened !
<坦白地说，那就是你 希望发生！
An accomplice, hidden in the thicket..
帮凶， 隐藏在灌木丛中
..bundles the victim into his black van..
..捆绑受害者 进入他的黑色货车。
..and dumps everything into the lake.
..并倾倒一切 进入湖中。
There is no lake around there.
周围没有湖。
You believe only what you can see, my poor man.
您相信只有看到的东西， 我可怜的人。
That is why you are led astray so often.
这就是为什么 你常常被误入歧途。
''I remember the place. There was a curve..
``我记得那个地方。 有一条曲线..
''..that rocked me in my seat.
''..那让我震惊
''And our train went through the station at Andelieux.''
``我们的火车经过了 Andelieux的车站。''
< I believe I've found it.
<我相信我已经找到了。
Close to the curve, there is a queer property, isolated.
靠近曲线，有 酷儿属性，孤立。
Ideal for disposing of a body.
处置身体的理想选择。
This is an obsession.
这是一种痴迷。
I have an intuition that Babette was right.
我有一个直觉 巴贝特是对的。
Don't talk to me about intuition.
不要跟我谈论直觉。
She doesn't have the imagination to invent such a story.
她没有想象力 发明这样的故事。
Then perhaps it was a hallucination.
然后也许是幻觉。
Aunt Babette is alright in the head.
巴贝特姨妈的脑袋还好。
She is a world authority on butterflies.
她是世界权威 在蝴蝶上。
She doesn't invent them. She catches them, and names them.
她没有发明它们。 她抓住了它们并命名。
She wants to do the same with the killer, and I will help her.
她想与 杀手，我会帮助她的。
One doesn't hunt a killer like a butterfly.
一个人不追杀人 像蝴蝶一样
No. It's the same. One traps them and - shlack - one pins them.
不，是一样的一个人困住他们 和-松散-固定他们。
''Shlack'' ! I don't understand.
``Shlack''！我不明白
That's because you don't listen !
那是因为你不听！
Have a good time with your friends of the Oval Thistle.
与您度过愉快的时光 椭圆蓟的朋友。
We won't be drinking water. Have no doubt !
我们不会喝水。 毫无疑问！
Bye. Have a safe trip !
再见一路平安 ！
Look at the Scotsman !
看苏格兰人！
They don't wear anything under their kilts, you know.
他们什么都不穿 在他们的短裙下，你知道。
How did I manage to do this ?
我如何做到这一点？
Can we help you ?
我们可以帮您吗？
Your hat.
你的帽子
I wonder who..
不知道是谁
..that girl might be ? - She could be the new maid..
..那个女孩可能是？ -她可能是新来的女仆。
..up at ''La Vallée aux Loups''.
..up在“ LaValléeaux Loups”。
None of them last very long.
他们都没有持续很长时间。
< Old Man Charpentier sees to that.
<老人夏庞帝 看到这一点。
< That poor girl...
<那个可怜的姑娘...
With all the snow out there..
所有的雪都在那里。
..she won't be catching a bus.
..她不会坐公共汽车。
There won't be a bus today. Can I take you somewhere ?
今天不会有公车。 我可以带你去哪里吗？
What luck you were there !
你在那里真幸运！
I am sure they would have all left me to freeze on the spot.
我相信他们会拥有所有 让我当场冻结。
Your seats are heated ?
你的座位加热了吗？
No-no, it's the motor you feel.
不，不，这是您感觉到的马达。
They are all dogs in that place.
他们都是那个地方的狗。
Like my employer, M. Charpentier.
像我的老板一样 夏潘捷先生。
He's a dog ? - A rat !
他是狗吗？ - 一只老鼠 ！
Rich beyond belief, but you'd never know it, the rat !
丰富得令人难以置信，但 你永远不会知道的，老鼠！
Always in the corridors, waiting to stare at me !
总是在走廊里 等着凝视我！
You know, staring...
你知道，凝视着……
Staring, how ? I can't tell you.
凝视，如何？ 我不能告诉你
He sends shivers down my spine.
他向我的脊椎发出寒战。
Fact is, Old Man Charpentier frightens everyone.
事实是，老人夏潘捷 吓到大家了
What do you do in the house of this old man ?
你在房子里做什么 这个老人呢？
Everything.  Washing-up, dusting, shopping, making beds.
一切。洗碗碟， 打扫灰尘，购物，铺床。
All by yourself ? No, there is Mme. Clairin.
靠你自己 ？ 不，有女士。克莱林
But the place is so large, it really needs an army.
但是这个地方很大 它真的需要一支军队。
Does he live there alone ?
他一个人住吗？
No, with his poor daughter and a gardener.
不，和他可怜的女儿 和一个园丁。
The worst thing is the kitchen.
最糟糕的是厨房。
It's like something out of the Middle Ages.
有点像 走出中世纪。
You've been there a long time ?
你去那儿很久了吗？
Seven weeks. I don't want to stay a moment longer.
七个星期。我不想 待一会儿。
Come in. I will fetch Mademoiselle.
进来吧。 我将拿来小姐。
The new domestic is here.
新的国内来了。
< Send her into my office. - Very well, Mademoiselle.
<送她到我的办公室。 -很好，小姐。
Come, she will see you now.
来吧，她现在见。
You are the 13th this year. Superstitious ?
您今年是第13位。 迷信？
Bonjour, I am Emma Charpentier.
你好， 我是Emma Charpentier。
You are a good cook ?
你是个好厨师吗？
You have references ? No, none.
你有参考吗？ 不，没有
That is quite unusual.
那是很不寻常的。
For the most part, they are of little value.
在大多数情况下， 它们没有什么价值。
They never say why one left a place.
他们从不说 为什么一个人离开一个地方。
Very true. What day would you prefer as a rest day ?
非常真实你哪一天 喜欢休息吗？
I am very flexible. Since the death of my dear husband...
我很灵活。以来 我亲爱的丈夫之死...
My time is my own.
我的时间是我自己的。
Very well. Let me show you your room.
很好。 让我告诉你你的房间。
I need more than a kitchen maid.
我不仅需要厨房女仆。
Mme. Clairin isn't here every day.
嗯克莱林不是每天都在这里。
My grandfather, he built the house. A fantastic man.
我的祖父，他建造了 屋。太棒了
But very strict. The damage was done by my father..
但是非常严格。 损坏是我父亲造成的。
..in a fit of anger. He refuses to let anyone repair it.
..有点生气。他拒绝 让任何人修理它。
My father is a difficult man.
我父亲是一个很难的人。
He keeps a close eye on expenses, and can be... difficult.
他一直在关注费用， 可能会很困难
- I am used to..
- 我习惯于..
..the habits of the elderly.
..老年人的习惯。
To begin with, things will be easy. There are four of us.
首先，事情将会是 简单。我们四个人。
Myself, my niece on vacation, her schoolfriend, and...
我自己，我的外nie女在度假， 她的同学，然后...
Emma !
艾玛！
..my father. But my brothers will be arriving for Christmas.
..我的父亲。但是我的兄弟们 即将圣诞节。
Emma !
艾玛！
These costings for Christmas. You wish to bankrupt me ?
这些圣诞节费用。 你想让我破产吗？
Who is that, over there ?
那是谁啊
The new kitchen maid I spoke to you about.
新厨房女佣 我跟你谈过
Come, come ! Let's see you, come here !
来来 ！ 我们来看你，过来！
What is your name, little one ? Prudence Beresford.
你叫什么名字，小家伙？ 保诚贝雷斯福德。
She's got good arms.
她的手臂很好。
Well then...
好吧...
Remember two things : I abhor waste..
记住两件事: 我讨厌浪费
..and a squire is not necessarily rich.
..一个乡绅是 不一定丰富。
I live here because I want to, not because I have the means.
我住在这里是因为我想 不是因为我有能力。
Now go ! Don't bother me further.
现在，走吧 ！ 不要再打扰我了。
Don't forget that a good cod does as well as a turbot.
别忘了一个好鳕鱼 和大菱形一样好。
I am sorry.
对不起。
Emma !
艾玛！
Come here, Emma !
过来，艾玛！
Excuse me.
劳驾。
I must go. Your room is at the top - on the left.
我必须去。你的房间是 在顶部-在左侧
The key is in the door.
钥匙在门上。
My own children have become my enemies !
我自己的孩子 成了我的敌人！
< Tell that idiot of a doctor that last medicine..
<告诉那个白痴医生 最后一种药..
< ..is no good at all !
<..一点都不好！
< Are you sure ? -< Of course !
<您确定吗？ -<当然可以！
Who is there ?
谁在那儿 ？
You must be the niece... of Mlle. Charpentier.
你一定是侄女... 的Mlle。夏蓬蒂
Yes, I am Alexie Charpentier.
是的，我是Alexie Charpentier。
And you, you are Mary Poppins ! - Ah ! Mary Poppins !
而你，你是玛丽·波平斯！ -啊！欢乐满人间 ！
You aren't my idea of a maid working for my grandfather.
你不是我的女仆 为我的祖父工作。
You aren't my idea of the niece of Mlle. Charpentier.
你不是我侄女的主意 的Mlle。夏蓬蒂
Mme. Clairin is waiting for you in the kitchen.
嗯克莱林在等你 在厨房。
Then let me change, and I'll be right there.
那让我改变 我会在那里。
I'll wait for you on the landing.
我会等你降落。
Emma !
艾玛！
Always he shouts after my aunt. Yet she's the only one who loves him.
他总是向我姨妈喊。 然而，她是唯一爱他的人。
Don't the others love him ? - They are like vultures.
别人不爱他吗？ -他们就像秃鹰。
They are waiting for him to die.
他们在等他死。
Who are the vultures ? - My uncles.
秃are是谁？ -我叔叔
Uncle Raphael. He is weird. A banker, and a gambler.
拉斐尔叔叔。他很奇怪。 一位银行家和一名赌徒。
He lives in Lyon, with his wife.
他和妻子一起住在里昂。
He likes only money and drugs.
他只喜欢钱和毒品。
Uncle Augustin lives on an island.
奥古斯丁叔叔住 在一个岛上。
He has abandoned sculpting to spend his time hunting.
他放弃了雕刻 花时间打猎。
The more he kills, the better he likes it.
他杀死的越多， 他越喜欢它。
And who looks after you ? - My father.
谁来照顾你？ - 我的父亲。
My mother is dead. The family consider him..
我妈妈死了。 一家人都考虑他。
..a failure. They call him ''Frederick the layabout''
..失败。他们叫他 弗雷德里克的闲逛
But I don't care. He is a good guitarist.
但是我不在乎。 他是一位优秀的吉他手。
It's through there.
就在那儿。
And there was Uncle Edmond, who died in the War.
还有爱德蒙叔叔， 在战争中丧生的人。
We're nearly there, come along.
我们快到了，来吧。
She's already had a tipple.
她已经喝醉了。
A little one for the road,..
一条小路，..
..Mme. Clairin ? - Weather as it is, it helps.
..Mme。克莱林？ -天气照旧，有帮助。
I've been waiting for you.
我一直在等你。
I'll show you where the things are.
我会给你看 东西在哪里。
It won't take a moment.
不会花一点时间。
In the scullery, there is everything you need for lunch.
在盘ull里，有 午餐所需的一切。
The stove is burning well. I lit it..
炉子烧得很好。 我点燃了
..this morning. You need to keep it stoked up.
..今天早上。 您需要保持它的状态。
It can get cold in the house.
屋子里可能会变冷。
I have made some coffee.
我煮了咖啡。
So, there you are. Goodbye !
所以，你在那里。 再见 ！
Take care, grandfather hates..
保重，爷爷讨厌。
..getting his meals late. Lunch is at noon, Mme. Poppins.
..晚饭。 午餐是中午，夫人。罂粟花。
Come on, or we'll be late !
来吧， 不然我们会迟到的！
< Now who's imagining things ? -< Papa, you exaggerate.
<现在谁在想象事情？ -<爸爸，你夸张了。
< I know what I'm talking about. My sickness, two weeks ago,..
<我知道我在说什么。 我的病，两个星期前..
..your brothers had something to do with that.
..你的兄弟有 与此有关。
What will you suggest next ?
接下来您会提出什么建议？
< It was only indigestion.
<只是消化不良。
< Now sit back and calm yourself.
<现在坐下来让自己平静。
< You talk to me about indigestion !
<您和我谈论消化不良！
Even your precious Dr. Lagarde was suspicious.
甚至是您珍贵的拉加德博士 很可疑
But you forget one thing.
但是你忘记了一件事。
Misers always die last.
失败总是死在最后。
The dumb waiter doesn't work.
愚蠢的服务生不工作。
The lead weights have fallen off.
铅的重量下降了。
Can it be repaired ? - I don't think so.
可以修理吗？ -我不这么认为。
Let us help you. There are only 30 seconds to midday.
让我们来帮助您。有 到中午只有30秒。
Mme. Poppins, Valerie, my best friend.
嗯罂粟花， 瓦莱丽，我最好的朋友。
Enchanted. Away you go. I'll follow.
着迷。 走开我会跟着
This is good, the soup.
这很好，汤。
It is good, really good, the soup.
很好 真的很好，汤。
''A sharp curve...''
``弯曲的曲线...''
Yes ? < Prudence Beresford !
是啊 <Prudence Beresford！
Finally ! Where are you ?
终于！你在哪 ？
Figure it out for yourself...
自己弄清楚...
Where are you ?
你在哪 ？
You haven't launched yourself into that ridiculous mystery..
你还没有发射自己 进入那个荒谬的奥秘。
..of the railway murder ?
..铁路谋杀案？
I have discovered a sudden passion for snow-shoes.
我突然发现 对雪鞋的热情。
I am practising on them.
我正在练习。
< What ? - Yes, I've never dared confess,..
<什么？ -是的，我从来不敢承认。
..but I have long dreamed of...
..但是我梦dream以求...
..walking alone in the snow, wearing snow-shoes.
..独自一人在雪中行走， 穿着雪鞋。
When are you coming back ?
你什么时候回来 ？
I'll be back...
我会回来的...
I don't know.
我不知道。
Make it within 5 days, it's Christmas !
5天内完成 是圣诞节！
Marie-Christine and her family will be spending it with us.
玛丽·克里斯汀和她的家人 将与我们一起度过。
Is it Christmas already ?
已经是圣诞节了吗？
But yes ! It comes round once a year.
但是，是的 ！ 每年一次。
How could I forget ?
我怎么会忘记？
Christmas, another chance to enjoy the grandchildren !
圣诞节，另一个机会 享受孙子们！
You are enjoying yourselves.
你们自己很开心。
We are off to the museum. - The museum ?
我们要去博物馆了。 - 博物馆 ？
The red house, where grandfather keeps his treasures.
红房子，祖父在哪里 保留他的宝藏。
It's beyond the rock over there.
它在那边的岩石之外。
Come on, it's through here !
来吧，通过这里！
This way.
这条路。
< Oh ! It's freezing in here !
<哦！这里很冷！
Remember to lock up, because of the wild boar.
记得锁起来 因为野猪。
You are not allowed here. This is the squire's museum.
您不可以在这里。 这是乡绅的博物馆。
Sit !!
坐!!
*This is the answerphone of Babette Boutiti.
*这是的应答电话 Babette Boutiti。
*I am hunting butterflies in Guiana.
*我在寻找蝴蝶 圭亚那
*Leave your message after the ''pop''.
*留言后 “流行”。
*Pop !
* Pop！
Aunt Babette, I have just discovered..
巴贝特姨妈 我刚发现..
..the body of a strangled woman..
..身体 被勒死的女人的画像。
..wearing a fur coat, with a red glove..
..穿着皮大衣， 一个红色的手套。
..in a large sarcophagus.
..在一个大石棺中。
There you are.  I will tell you more when you return.
你在这。我会告诉 你回来的时候会更多。
Good, that's all for now.
好，仅此而已。
Belisaire !
Belisaire！
Rotten sod !
烂草皮！
Is it still Christmas ?
现在还在圣诞节吗？
I've never seen that woman before, I'm certain.
我从没见过那个女人 之前，我确定。
Are you alright ? You look very pale, Emma.
你还好吗 ？ 你看起来很苍白，艾玛。
It will pass. I'm okay, thank you.
会过去的。 我很好，谢谢。
There we are. Now breathe slowly.
我们到了。 现在慢慢呼吸。
Thank you for being here, Francois.
非常感谢您的到来， 弗朗索瓦
Whenever you need me.
每当你需要我的时候。
Breathe slowly.
慢慢呼吸。
< Inspector Blache,..
<布莱奇检查员..
..Dr Lagarde. - Hello.
..拉加德博士。 - 你好。
Doctor.
医生。
This is unbelievable !
太不可思议了 ！
The sarcophagus is from the 18th dynasty !
石棺来自 18王朝！
I bought it more than 50 years ago !
我买了它 50多年前！
Now it's in pieces !
现在是碎片！
All because a stupid creature decided to be killed inside !
都是因为一个愚蠢的生物 决定在里面被杀！
It is appalling.
令人震惊。
M. Charpentier, go back to the chateau.
M. Charpentier， 回到城堡。
Give him a whisky, I will meet with you later.
给他威士忌， 我待会儿见。
Many of my elderly patients..
我很多老年患者
..play the invalid to oppress their relatives.
..播放无效 压迫他们的亲戚。
Inspector, who discovered the body ?
督察 谁发现了尸体？
The new employee.
新员工。
You went to the ''museum''..
您去了“博物馆”。
..and forced the lid off the sarcophagus.
..然后将盖子从 石棺。
Yes.
是。
For what reason ? - I was looking for a body.
是什么原因 ？ -我在找尸体。
A body ? So you knew there was one there ?
身体 ？所以你知道那里 有一个吗？
Yes, of course. - Furthermore, I will explain.
当然是。 -再说吧。
It all started with Aunt Babette before she left to hunt butterflies...
一切始于巴贝特姨妈 在她去狩猎蝴蝶之前...
I cannot tell you. Stone dead !
我不能告诉你。 石死了！
And that made me...
那让我...
You expect me to swallow that ? - You can check.
您希望我将其吞下吗？ -您可以检查。
My aunt made a statement to the railway authorities in Andelieux.
我姨妈向 安德列厄铁路当局。
Your name, if you please ?
请问您的名字？
Mme. Beresford. The Widow Beresford.
嗯贝雷斯福德。 寡妇贝雷斯福德。
Perhaps you are related to Colonel Beresford ?
也许您与 贝雷斯福德上校？
It is a common name. There are plenty in this region.
这是一个通用名称。 这个地区有很多。
Excuse me, I would like to get back to work.
对不起，我想得到 回去工作。
I'm sorry, I should have recognised Mme. Beresford.
对不起，我应该有 公认的女士贝雷斯福德。
But I saw her for a very short time.
但是我看到她 在很短的时间内。
She said she was there to practise using snow-shoes !
她说她在那里 练习使用雪鞋！
I'll give her snow-shoes, just you see !
我给她雪鞋 就看你！
What'd you say ? - Nothing. Speaking to myself.
你说什么 - 没有。自言自语。
She must stop this farce ! - She could be of help to us.
她必须停止这场闹剧！ -她可能对我们有帮助。
If you accompany me, you'll have to use another name.
如果你陪我，你会 必须使用其他名称。
And why ?
又为什么呢？
To protect her. There has been a murder there.
为了保护她 那里发生了谋杀案。
And I forgot to tell you...
我忘了告诉你
Mme. Prudence is passing herself off as a widow.
嗯审慎度过 自己当寡妇
Mme. Prudence, a widow ?!
嗯审慎，寡妇？！
Ha-ha-ha ! Fancy her thinking of that one !
哈哈哈！ 看中她的那个想法！
Enough. I suggest we talk indoors.
足够。 我建议我们在室内聊天。
The death happened when ? - Pathologist says 2 weeks ago.
死亡发生在什么时候？ -病理学家说2周前。
But, according to your aunt, she was killed on 28 November..
但是，根据你阿姨的说法 她于11月28日被杀。
..on the Morgan-Bellefond express train.
..在Morgan-Bellefond 快速列车。
Then the corpse was dragged to and hidden in the sarcophagus.
然后将尸体拖到 并隐藏在石棺中。
But what led the killer to open the sarcophagus ?
但是导致杀手的原因 打开石棺？
''You believe only what you see.''
``你只相信什么 你看。''
''That is why you are led astray so often.''
``这就是为什么你是 经常误入歧途。''
''Use your imagination.''
''动用你的想象力。''
There is no evidence any of the Charpentiers are involved.
没有任何证据 夏邦人参与其中。
"Except that I found the body on their property.''
“除了我发现了尸体 在他们的财产上。''
< Colonel ?
<上校？
Colonel, Colonel... - Yes... as I was saying...
上校上校 -是的...正如我所说的...
I was listening to you. What do you know about them ?
我在听你 您对它们了解多少？
You will meet them. They are all at the chateau...
你会遇到他们的。他们是 全部在城堡...
A lovers' quarrel turned out badly. And there you are !
恋人吵架了 不好而且你在那里！
I will speak to Inspector Blavache.
我会跟 布拉瓦切督察。
- Blache, Monsieur.
-Blache， 先生
I will tell Blavache none of us have ever seen this woman.
我不会告诉布拉瓦什 我们见过这个女人。
And you will all say the same.
你们都会说相同的话。
Are you sure, father ?
你确定吗，父亲？
Perhaps she was one of Raphael's little friends.
也许她是拉斐尔的一员 小朋友。
That's some joke, that is !
那是个玩笑，那就是！
That must be Dr Lagarde. Let him in.
那一定是拉加德博士。 让他进来。
Still looking for the fountain of youth, father ?
还在寻找 青春的源泉，父亲？
That isn't funny, Augustin.
不好笑，奥古斯丁。
Lean on me, father.
靠我，父亲。
I will outlast all of you..
我会比所有人都持久。
..just to protect my property from your predatory grasp.
..只是为了保护我的财产 从掠夺性的掌握。
The police..
警察..
..will soon be here to interrogate you.
..将很快在这里 去问你
You'd better prepare your alibis !
你最好准备 你的辩解！
Why did you open the sarcophagus ?
你为什么打开 石棺？
I saw the cover had been lifted recently.
我看到了封面 最近被解除了。
I was overcome with curiosity.
我被好奇心克服了。
I have always been a frustrated archaeologist.
我一直 沮丧的考古学家。
What more can you tell us ?
您还能告诉我们什么？
I was, how shall I say,... overcome by the smell.
我当时是怎么说... 通过气味克服。
That sickly smell of death.
那令人恶心的死亡气味。
That's all. I don't wish to go into details.
就这样。我不希望 进入细节。
Isn't it horrifying ?! That poor woman coming here to die.
是不是很恐怖？那 可怜的女人来这里死亡。
< Forget it. We didn't know her.
<算了。 我们不认识她。
She came here by chance. - How do you know ?
她是偶然来的。 - 你怎么知道的 ？
If it really was by chance, why is Emma..
如果真的是偶然的话 为什么艾玛..
..so troubled ? -< Why are you surprised..
..这么麻烦吗？ -<你为什么感到惊讶..
..that a murder should trouble her ?
..谋杀应 麻烦她了吗？
He thinks like an artist.
他像艺术家一样思考。
Why do you always prod people as if they were animals ?
你为什么总是刺人 好像它们是动物？
That is enough !
足够了 ！
This is not the time for bickering!
现在不是时候 争吵！
< The police believe the crime took place on 28 November.
<警方相信犯罪 于11月28日举行。
< How did they learn that so fast ? -< It's not the 19th Century.
<他们怎么这么快学到的？ -<不是19世纪。
< That's not much to brag about.
<没什么可吹牛的。
< Friday the 28th. It was the day Emma invited us here.
<28日星期五。那是 那天爱玛邀请我们来这里。
< So what ? -< By that night, we were all here.
<那又怎样呢？ -<那天晚上，我们都在这里。
< And ? -< It will interest the police.
<然后？ -<它将引起警察的注意。
< What about the theory of a lovers' quarrel ?
<理论如何？ 恋人的争吵？
< Not the 1st time Papa's museum was used as a meeting place.
<不是第一次帕帕博物馆 被用作聚会场所。
< Lovers meeting in Papa's museum ?!
<恋人在爸爸的聚会 博物馆 ？！
I have a problem imagining that..
我在想象中有一个问题。
..it's like the inside of a glacier during Winter.
..就像一个内部 冬季的冰川。
Your daughter is lovely.
你女儿很可爱。
She, and her friend, are are excited by this crime.
她和她的朋友是 对这种罪行感到兴奋。
It's their age.
这是他们的年龄。
Papa, the Inspector is here with another gentleman.
爸爸，检查员在这里 与另一位先生。
Our new employee, Mme. Beresford, recently arrived.
我们的新员工，女士。贝雷斯福德， 最近到了。
The Widow Beresford, I presume ?
我想寡妇贝雷斯福德？
Pardon me, I have a terrible cold.
对不起， 我感冒了。
We need you to attend the police station.
我们需要您参加 警察局。
One of my officers will accompany you, if you are well enough.
我的一名官员将陪伴 你，如果你足够好。
Ask for me, my name is ''Colonel Snowshoe'' !
问我，我的名字是 上校雪鞋！
Good, we would first like..
好，我们首先要..
..to interrogate your brothers.
..讯问你的兄弟。
You are wasting your time, Inspector.
你在浪费时间 检查员
If that woman had ever stayed here, my father or I..
如果那个女人曾经留下来 在这里，我还是我父亲
..would have recognised her.
..会认出她的。
< Everything seems to suggest..
<一切似乎都在暗示..
<..that the victim was not from around here.
<..那个受害者不是 从这里来。
< She was a stranger. - A Russian ?
<她是一个陌生人。 -俄罗斯人？
< Girls, this is not a conversation for your ears.
<女生，这不是 耳边的对话。
Mme. Beresford, conduct the gentlemen upstairs.
嗯贝雷斯福德，进行 楼上的先生们。
Very well.
很好。
I am going to see my father.
我要去见父亲。
Gentlemen, I will show the way.
先生们， 我会指出路的。
So, I am dead, am I?
所以，我死了，对吗？
Francois !
弗朗索瓦！
Your father is in good form. The murder has envigorated him.
你父亲身体状况很好。 谋杀使他兴奋了。
What is it, Emma ?
是什么事，艾玛？
What is wrong ?
怎么了 ？
I think there is a criminal in the family.
我认为有罪犯 在家庭中。
Why do you think that ?
为什么你这么想 ？
Because of Martina,..
因为Martina，..
..my brother Edmond's wife, who was meant to come here.
..我的兄弟埃德蒙的妻子， 谁该来这里的
Ah yes, is there any news ? - No, that's just it.
是的，有什么消息吗？ -不，就是这样。
The police think that the victim comes from the East.
警察认为 受害者来自东方。
And you think the dead woman might be Martina ? - Yes.
你以为死去的女人 可能是马丁娜？ -是的
I am frightened of telling the police about this.
我很害怕告诉 警察对此。
Have you spoken to your brothers ? No, I can't judge their reaction.
你和兄弟们说话了吗？ 不，我无法判断他们的反应。
Emma, I know you.
艾玛 我认识你。
If you don't speak of your fears, you will make yourself sick.
如果你不说恐惧 你会让自己恶心。
Then I should go to the police ? - Yes.
那我应该去警察局吗？ -是的
Gentlemen, this way.
先生们， 这条路。
May I take your coat ?
我可以把你的外套给我吗？
Never during an enquiry.
从来没有询问。
Thank you, madam. - I shall stay.
谢谢夫人。 -我留下。
You will leave, madam.
你将离开， 夫人。
You stinker !
你臭！
Without me, you are nothing.
没有我，你什么都不是。
Nothing ! Nothing at all !
没有 ！没事！
A moment, let me think. When did you arrive ?
片刻，让我想一想。 你什么时候到达 ？
A little over three weeks ago to see my father.
三周前 去见我父亲
You live away from here ? - Yes, I spend my time in Paris.
你住这里吗？ -是的，我在巴黎呆了时间。
I stayed here for two days, at the end of November.
我在这里住了两天 在十一月底。
< She was killed, when ? -< End of November.
<她被杀死的时候是什么？ -<11月底。
You are married ? Your wife..
你结婚了 ？ 你妻子..
..is not here with you ?
..不在这里吗？
She hates Winter in France.
她讨厌法国的冬天。
< Do you come here often ?
<你经常来这里吗？
< From time to time, to see my sister.
<不时 去见我姐姐
The last time, when was that ? - Three weeks ago.
上一次是什么时候？ - 三个星期前。
The end of November ?
11月底？
Yes, end of November.
是的，11月底。
How do you get on with your father ?
你如何相处 你父亲
None of his children get on with my father.
他的孩子都没有上 和我爸。
Even Emma has problems. He is such a skinflint.
甚至Emma都有问题。 他真是个skin子。
It was my grandfather's fault.
这是我祖父的错。
Why ?
为什么呢
He hated Papa, and took his revenge in his Will.
他讨厌爸爸，并把他的 报仇
Emma, my brothers and I share ownership of the fortune.
艾玛，我的兄弟和我分享 财产的所有权。
He only retains the right to live here.
他只保留权利 住这里
He cannot sell anything, decide anything, and it drives him crazy !
他什么都不能卖，决定 任何事情，都会使他发疯！
You come here often ? - Sometimes, with my daughter.
你经常来这里吗？ -有时和我的女儿。
< Why were you all gathered here at the end of November ?
<你们为什么都聚集 11月底在这里？
No reason. It was just a family get-together.
没有理由。这只是 一个家庭聚会。
Where everyone hates each other...
每个人都讨厌彼此的地方
Police enter my house without asking the head of family !
警察没有进入我家 问一家之主！
Who is the head here ?
谁是这里的负责人？
< Answer me !
<回答我！
< You are, but we wanted to avoid tiring you.
<您是，但我们想要 避免累你。
Dr Lagarde..
拉加德博士
..said... - Him. If I listened to him,..
..说过... -他如果我听他的话..
..I would never get out of bed.
..我永远也不会起床。
The prescription he signed, gave me indigestion for 3 weeks !
他签的处方 给我消化了三个星期！
He almost..
他差点..
..poisoned me !
..毒死了我！
I must admit that was when we still had the old cook.
我必须承认那是什么时候 我们还有老厨师。
This new one, here now, she is a pearl !
这个新的，现在在这里， 她是珍珠！
Well rounded.. like an eclair !
圆润的..像泡芙！
< Rounded like an eclair ? - Ssh !
<像泡芙一样圆润？ -嘘！
Haven't you noticed ? - I haven't got that near.
你没注意到吗？ -还没到那儿。
Well, then...
好吧...
What are your assumptions about this case ?
你的假设是什么 关于这种情况？
It's a little early to talk about assumptions,..
谈论还为时过早 关于假设，..
..especially since we don't yet know who the woman was.
..尤其是因为我们不 还不知道那个女人是谁
A stranger, it seems.
看来是个陌生人。
Perhaps a conquest of my son, Augustin.
也许是我儿子的征服 奥古斯丁。
He says he didn't recognise her.
他说他没有 认出她。
That means nothing. It's got him jittery.
那没什么。 这让他很紧张。
My sons are all cowards, and liars,..
我儿子都是胆小鬼 和骗子，..
..a bunch of vultures who are waiting for my death.
..一群秃are 等待我的死亡。
I'm starting to feel very ill. Emma !
我开始病得很重。 艾玛！
I must have a lie-down.
我必须躺下。
He doesn't feel much love for his children !
他没有太多的爱 为他的孩子们！
He hasn't forgiven them for disinheriting him.
他没有原谅他们 取消了他的继承权。
Au revoir, Colonel.
上校
What is that ?
那是什么 ？
Belisaire, don't be an idiot !
Belisaire， 不要白痴！
I didn't see anything !
我什么都没看见！
Come on, open the boot !
来吧，打开靴子！
I am dead. A dead man can't open boots for his widow.
我死了。死人不能 为他的寡妇打开靴子。
I said it on the spur of the moment, I was joking.
我说是出于刺激 此刻，我在开玩笑。
The fact you said it makes it other than a joke.
你说的事实使 除了开玩笑。
Alright, I said it. Now open the boot ! Belisaire !
好吧，我说了。现在 打开靴子！ Belisaire！
The soon-to-be widower Belisaire !
即将成为w夫 Belisaire！
Come on ! Oh, this can't be happening !
来吧 ！ 哦，这不可能发生！
Belisaire...
Belisaire ...
You are offended because I was right. It's as simple as that.
你被冒犯了，因为我曾经 对。就这么简单。
Belisaire, enough is enough, let me out.
Belisaire，够了， 让我出去。
Let me out !
让我出去 ！
What has happened ?
发生了什么 ？
The Spotted Leopard !
斑豹！
Belisaire ?
Belisaire？
You found the body, and completed your mission.
你找到了尸体 完成了你的任务
Now, you can return home.
现在，您可以回家了。
Why ?
为什么呢
I'm tired of seeing my wife disguised as a kitchen maid !
我厌倦了见我的妻子 伪装成厨房女仆！
As to your other activities, I hold my tongue.
至于你的其他活动， 我握住我的舌头。
Always cooking for others, but never for me.
总是为别人做饭， 但永远不会对我
You forget my chicken in salt. - That was ten years ago.
你忘了我的盐鸡。 -那是十年前。
And, most important, I must repeat - Christmas is here..
而且，最重要的是，我必须 重复-圣诞节在这里。
The children want to hear the chiming of the bells.
孩子们想听 钟声。
Comes from their Swiss side, without a doubt.
来自瑞士这边 毫无疑问。
I'd like to take a look at the autopsy photos.
我想看看 验尸照片。
This is a dancer. - Pardon ?
这是一个舞者。 -赦免？
The victim was a dancer. Look at her feet.
受害人是一名舞者。 看她的脚。
See if any dancers recognise her, but not classical.
看看舞者是否认识到 她，但不是古典。
Why not classical ?
为什么不古典？
A classical dancer's feet would show more punishment.
古典舞者的脚 会表现出更多的惩罚。
Impressive, Holmes. - Elementary, my dear Watson.
令人印象深刻，福尔摩斯。 -小学，亲爱的沃森。
Now, there is no question of me being taken off the case.
现在，毫无疑问 我被解雇了。
Nor away from the fancy men who gather round you.
也不远离幻想的人 谁聚集在你周围。
Oh ! You are jealous ?
喔！你吃醋 ？
I think that's sweet !
我认为那太好了！
Well, now, my dear Colonel Beresford,...
现在好了， 我亲爱的贝雷斯福德上校，...
..while this was delightful, I must return to my kitchen.
..虽然这很令人愉快， 我必须回到我的厨房。
You forget one thing :..
你忘记了一件事:
having found the body puts you in a difficult position.
找到了尸体 你处境艰难。
You are my number one suspect. I must hold you in custody.
你是我的第一嫌疑犯。 我必须关押你。
I will notify your employer.
我会通知您的雇主。
In custody - throughout the night ?
拘留期间 晚上？
Yes. But not in a police cell.
是。但不在警察牢房中。
You always yield to temptation !
你总是屈服于诱惑！
Especially when driven by envy.
尤其是在嫉妒驱使下。
Ah, there you are.
啊，你来了。
You free from police custody ? How was it ?
您免于警察拘留吗？ 它怎么样 ？
It was fine. But I never thought I'd be held like that.
很好但是我从来没有 以为我会被这样拘留。
What is this place ? - My old workshop.
这是什么地方 ？ -我的老作坊。
Nothing has been finished here for two years.
一切还没有完成 在这里两年。
You abandoned it just on a whim ?
你放弃了 只是一时兴起？
No. I felt the need to see some Mediterranean light.
不，我觉得有必要看 一些地中海的光芒。
You will wait for me ?
你会等我吗？
What is it this time ?
这次是什么？
< I must talk with you. -< Have you heard anything ?
<我必须和你谈谈。 -<你听到什么了吗？
< I think that the victim might be Martina.
<我认为受害者 可能是马丁娜。
Martina ? - Her telegram was so weird.
马丁娜（Martina）？ -她的电报太奇怪了。
After she'd already written that she was coming.
她已经写完了 她来了。
I should tell the police. - It's nothing to do with them.
我应该告诉警察。 -和他们无关。
< I am worried. I don't know what to do.
<我很担心。 我不知道该怎么办。
Just say nothing. Do nothing.
没话说没做什么。
I was told you have a fondness for painting women.
有人告诉我你很喜欢 为绘画女性。
No. I don't paint women, I acquire them.
不，我不画女人 我获得它们。
It is the sea I paint. The stones, the light.
我画的是大海。 石头，光。
But not people. - No, not people.
但不是人。 -不，不是人。
They are too complicated. - Mm...
他们太复杂了。 -嗯...
I don't understand why a woman like you is here.
我不明白为什么 像你这样的女人在这里
What do you want me to say ?
你想让我说什么 ？
Say nothing at all.
什么也没说。
So many prejudices, for an artist !
这么多的偏见， 对于一个艺术家！
Do you like making beds, working in the kitchen ?
你喜欢铺床吗 在厨房工作？
Well enough. Cooking requires imagination..
足够好。烹饪 需要想象力。
..and the rest of it satisfies my taste for order.
..其余的都满足 我对订单的品味。
I would like to paint your portrait, one day.
我想画 你的肖像，有一天。
There she is ! A spy ! Grab her !
她在这里 ！间谍！ 抓住她 ！
A SPY !
一个间谍！
Tie her to the pole ! Dirty spy ! Quickly !
把她绑在杆子上！ 肮脏的间谍！快点！
SPY !
间谍！
Aim for the heart !
瞄准心脏！
Die ! Die, you bitch !
死 ！死了，你这bit子！
Aim !
目标 ！
Fire !
火 ！
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你的到来。
Excuse me, I am moved...
打扰一下，我很感动...
because I haven't entered here since the death of Edmond.
因为我还没进来 自从埃德蒙德（Edmond）死后。
He wrote to me, just before his death.
他写信给我 就在他去世之前。
He had met a Russian woman, Martina. They were getting married.
他遇到了一个俄罗斯女人， 马蒂娜他们要结婚了。
I learnt of his death just after receiving the letter.
我才知道他的死 收到信后
I didn't know what became of this Martina.
我不知道变成了什么 这个玛蒂娜酒。
I only knew her first name, and I forgot about her.
我只知道她的名字 我忘了她
But, a few weeks ago, I received a letter from Lyon..
但是，几周前，我 收到里昂的来信。
..signed Martina Charpentier.
..签名马丁娜·夏彭蒂埃。
''... I hope this letter does not distress you.
''...我希望这封信能 不要让你难过
''I don't even know if Edmond told you of our marriage.
``我什至不知道埃德蒙德 告诉你我们的婚姻。
''After his death, I found it too hard to write to you.
``他死后我找到了 写给你太难了。
''I have rebuilt my life, but my situation has changed.
``我重建了生活，但是 我的情况已经改变。
''I am writing to you because of my son.
''我正在给你写信 因为我儿子
''He is your brother's child. I don't have the means to raise him.
``他是你兄弟的孩子。 我没有办法抚养他。
''I am spending a few weeks in France.
``我花了几个星期 在法国。
''May we meet up ? I don't want to cause you pain.''
``我们可以见面吗？我不 想让你痛苦。''
I loved Edmond very much.
我非常爱埃德蒙。
He was my favourite brother. Then, the idea he had a son...
他是我最喜欢的兄弟。 然后，他有了儿子的想法...
I invited this woman to our house, for the end of November.
我邀请这个女人来我们 房子，到11月底。
So she could meet the family ? - Yes, that's right.
这样她可以见到家人吗？ - 恩，那就对了。
I just wanted them all to meet her.
我只想要他们 去见她
Augustin didn't take the matter seriously.
奥古斯丁没有 认真的
Raphael was very sceptical.
拉斐尔非常怀疑。
Frederick was the only one to believe it, with me.
弗雷德里克（Frederick）是唯一的 和我一起去相信它。
Then what happened ?
那怎么了？
The day when she was expected, I received a telegram.
期待她的那天， 我收到电报。
''Sorry. Problems. Have to leave...''
''抱歉。问题。 必须离开...''
And then, nothing more.
然后，仅此而已。
So, when you told me this woman..
所以，当你告诉我 这个女人..
..was foreign, I thought..
我以为是外国人
..that perhaps it was her.
..也许是她。
And, since then, the thought has obsessed me.
从那时起， 使我着迷。
With regard to strangers,..
关于陌生人，..
..what do you make of this Mme. Beresford ?
..你怎么看的 嗯贝雷斯福德？
Prudence ?
审慎？
I've not given her any thought, have you ?
我没有想她 你有吗
< She is an efficient woman and certainly highly intelligent.
<她是一个有效率的女人 当然是高度聪明的
And your brothers ?
和你的兄弟们？
Your father ?
你爸爸
They are all of one mind. She has bewitched them all.
他们全都一心一意。 她把所有的一切都迷住了。
My God, I will strangle her ! - Pardon me ?
天哪，我会勒死她！ - 对不起 ？
< Oh, nothing. Don't torment yourself. We will soon..
<哦，什么都没有。不要折磨 你自己我们会尽快..
..clear this matter up. You were right to talk to me.
..解决这件事。 你跟我说话是对的。
What are you going to do ?
你会怎样做 ？
Check the whereabouts of the three brothers..
检查行踪 三兄弟
..and go through the entire house with a fine tooth comb.
..并遍历整个 房子用细齿梳子。
I have an idea that she might be a dancer...
我有一个想法 她可能是一个舞蹈家...
It was my idea, Belisaire !
这是我的主意，Belisaire！
To be fair, Prudence had the idea of asking among dancers..
公平地说，Prudence拥有 在舞者中问的想法。
..to find the solution.
..找到解决方案。
Distribute photos of the victim.
分发受害者的照片。
Hop it ! You've no right here. Out !
跳吧！你在这里不对。 出来！
Lieut. Margaret Brown !
姐姐玛格丽特·布朗！
From the intelligence service to here !
从情报 服务到这里！
This could be anyone.
可以是任何人。
One of your dancers hasn't suddenly disappeared ?
您的一位舞者还没有 突然消失了吗？
Colonel, the girls here come and go like the wind.
上校，这里的女孩来 随风而去
Did one of them leave... around the end of November ?
他们之一离开了吗？ 11月底左右？
Anna Karenine. - A Russian ?
安娜·卡列宁（Anna Karenine）。 -俄罗斯人？
Yes, maybe Polish. Here, it's the Foreign Legion.
是的，也许是波兰人。 这是外国军团
Anna Karenine. She left here at the end of November.
安娜·卡列宁（Anna Karenine）。她离开这里 在十一月底。
She said she wanted to be reconciled with her husband.
她说她想成为 与丈夫和解。
She went to meet with him somewhere in the country.
她去见他了 在该国的某个地方。
She worked with you, how long ?
她和你一起工作 多久 ？
Six weeks, almost. Just an ordinary girl.
差不多六个星期了。 只是一个普通的女孩。
She said she was going on a cruise with an Englishman.
她说她要继续 和英国人一起航行。
In any event, it was just a story.
在任何情况下， 这只是一个故事。
I think she was Polish.
我认为她是波兰人。
And Catholic : she never missed Mass.
和天主教徒: 她从未错过过弥撒。
That's a point.
这就是重点。
Only the Polish still believe.
只有波兰人仍然相信。
She was still a liar.
她仍然是个骗子。
I don't agree.
我不同意
The policemen from the other day want to interrogate you.
其他警察 天想问你。
Pardon ?
原谅？
THEY WANT TO INTERROGATE YOU !
他们想问问你！
Please excuse me.
请原谅我。
Your orange juice is in the kitchen.
你的橙汁是 在厨房。
Where did you get Mme. Beresford ? From an agency ?
你从哪里得到的女士。贝雷斯福德？ 来自代理商？
No. A friend of a former maid told her..
号前女佣的朋友 告诉她..
..that we had a place free. -< So, you engaged..
..我们有一个自由的地方。 -<所以，你订婚了..
..a stranger who barely arrived..
..一个刚到的陌生人..
..before digging up a corpse !
..在挖尸之前！
Why don't you stop picking on your sister ?
你为什么不停止采摘 在你姐姐身上？
< Look here, medical man, you've got a fine cheek..
<看这里，医生， 你的脸颊很好。
..you're the one who told Emma to talk to the police.
..你是那个告诉 艾玛与警察交谈。
Don't be so insulting. - Now the police are holding us.
别那么侮辱 -现在警察在抓我们。
< They think we are responsible for Martina's disappearance.
<他们认为我们有责任 因为马丁娜的失踪。
< If she is the dead woman...
<如果她是死去的女人...
I'm going to see your father.
我去看望你父亲。
The cake was delicious. - Mme. Beresford baked it.
蛋糕很好吃。 -女士贝雷斯福德烤了它。
The number of recipes I have remembered !
食谱数 我记得了！
It's like skiing, one never forgets.
就像滑雪， 一个永远不会忘记的人。
I doubt this will help to advance the investigation.
我怀疑这将有助于 推进调查。
But you have forgotten one fundamental thing.
但是你忘记了 一件事
Oh yes ? What's that ? - My birthday.
哦，是吗？那是什么 ？ - 我的生日。
I don't know what to think. It's the 1st time you've forgotten.
我不知道该怎么想 这是您第一次忘记。
Is it the 22nd ?
是22号吗？
The 22nd of December, the birth of Belisaire Beresford.
12月22日， Belisaire Beresford的出生。
Oh sweet Jesus !
噢，天哪！
You will have to accompany me to the police station, madam.
你要陪我 到警察局警察局
Very well, monsieur. I will get my coat.
很好，先生。 我去买外套。
Any news, M. Snowshoe ? - Patience, patience.
有什么消息吗，雪鞋先生？ -耐心，耐心。
The little ones are charming. - Very.
小家伙很迷人。 -非常
I want to manufacture a few false clues for them.
我要制造 给他们一些错误的线索。
I don't understand. - I will leave a note, like..
我不明白 -我会留下纸条，像..
..''Martina, if you wish to live, stay away from the chateau.''
马丁娜，如果你想生活， 远离城堡。''
Why would you do that ?
为什么要这么做 ？
The poor things, they ferret around and remain empty-handed.
可怜的东西，他们鼬 周围，​​空手而归。
A clue would..
一个线索会..
..place them in danger.
..将他们置于危险之中。
You do realise a murderer is perhaps in there ?
你确实认识一个杀人犯 也许在里面？
Monsieur, this is Huguette, one of Margaret Brown's dancers.
先生，这是Huguette， 玛格丽特·布朗（Margaret Brown）的舞者之一。
I have received a card from Anna.
我已经收到了 安娜
Anna Karenine ? -*From Saint-Barth'.
安娜·卡列宁（Anna Karenine）？ -*来自圣巴特。
When did she post it ?
她什么时候发布的？
The date-stamp... Wait...
日期戳...等等...
14 or 17 December, it's not very clear.
12月14日或17日， 这不是很清楚。
17 December ? -*It was true about the Englishman.
12月17日？ -*关于英国人，这是真的。
Exit Anna Karenine.
退出Anna Karenine。
A dancer has received a card from her in the West Indies.
一位舞者收到了一张卡片 来自西印度群岛的她。
So, we come back to Martina Charpentier.
所以，我们回到 玛蒂娜（Martina Charpentier）。
The widow who didn't show up.
没有出现的寡妇。
Everything points to the Charpentier children..
一切都指向 夏邦儿童
..deciding not to split their inheritance..
..决定不分割他们的 遗产..
..with the new heir.
..与新的继承人。
Let's find out which of them profits most from the crime.
让我们找出其中的一个 从犯罪中获利最多。
As long as Old Man Charpentier lives, no-one will benefit.
只要老汉 生活，没有人会受益。
I wonder if Dr. Lagarde ever suspected..
我想知道拉加德博士 曾经怀疑..
..that someone attempted to kill the old man ?
..有人试图 杀死老人？
His symptoms were the same as poisoning with arsenic.
他的症状与 砷中毒。
We know that a number of people would be interested in...
我们知道很多人 对...感兴趣
What shall we say...
我们该怎么说...
Hastening his demise.
加快他的灭亡。
Mm... But the poisoner, after he had failed,..
嗯...但是中毒者 他失败后..
..would have increased the dose. But he didn't.
..将增加剂量。 但是他没有。
Yes, that doesn't make sense. Curious !
是的，那没有道理。 很好奇！
You've been their doctor, how long ?
你去过他们的医生 多久 ？
M. Charpentier was my first patient after my arrival,..
Charpentier先生是我的第一个 我抵达后有耐心..
..following the death of my wife.
..继我妻子去世之后。
Is something wrong ?
有什么事吗
I'm the only one without an alibi. That worries me.
我是唯一一个没有 阿里比。那让我担心。
Raphael was able to provide a detailed timetable.
拉斐尔有能力提供 详细的时间表。
Augustin was, of course, with a girl.
奥古斯丁当然是 和一个女孩。
Why do you say ''of course'' ?
你为什么说“当然”？
He is a womaniser, haven't you noticed ?
他是个女人 你没注意到吗？
Beneath his air of being an artist, he has no feelings.
在他的气质之下 艺术家，他没有感情。
Apart from Emma, he doesn't like people. - What were you doing, that day ?
除了艾玛，他不喜欢别人。 -那天你在做什么？
The passage of my days don't interest me any.
我日子的流逝 没兴趣
< What is there worth remembering ?
<有什么价值 还记得吗？
It seems to me you should try to remember.
在我看来你应该 试图记住。
I don't much like looking back.
我不太喜欢回头。
It is good having you here.
很高兴你在这里。
You are cheerful, joyful. You are always singing.
你开朗，快乐。 你总是在唱歌。
Especially when I am cooking.
特别是当我做饭的时候。
Meals are like plants.
膳食就像植物。
They are better with a song.
他们唱一首歌更好。
For me, cooking is rather like jazz.
对我来说，做饭比较 像爵士乐。
Beef on a string, where you mix raw and cooked meat,..
牛肉串，你在那里 将生肉和熟肉混合在一起..
..is rather like mouthing a trumpet.
..就像是张口 小号。
The way it boils !
沸腾的方式！
As for oysters, as the Martyr tells us,..
至于牡蛎， the道者告诉我们，..
..they are like the first Christians, eaten by lions,..
..他们就像第一个 基督徒被狮子吃了..
..only a requiem will do !
..只有一张遗嘱才行！
You enliven the kitchen. You remind me of my wife.
你使厨房变得活跃起来。 你让我想起了我的妻子。
She spread joy everywhere, and was not intimidated by my father.
她到处散布欢乐， 没被我父亲吓倒。
In fact, she got on well with him.
其实她相处得很好 和他一起。
But not you ?
但是不是吗？
He is obsessed with money.
他沉迷于金钱。
He is sitting on a pile of gold without being able to touch it.
他坐在一堆金子上 不能碰它。
Name of God ! They even run between your feet.
神的名字！他们甚至跑 在你的脚之间。
Do you enjoy hunting ? - No, only killing.
你喜欢打猎吗？ -不，只有杀人。
You've been running. - Yes...
您一直在跑步。 -是的...
You have red cheeks, I like that a lot.
你的脸颊红了 我非常喜欢那个。
What ? Madam prefers older men, perhaps ?
什么 ？夫人更喜欢 年长的男人，也许？
Your younger brothers are not bad. Excuse me.
你弟弟是 不错。劳驾。
Colonel Snowshoe, we have found a clue.
雪靴上校， 我们找到了一个线索。
It is proof that Martina was coming here.
这证明了玛蒂娜 来这里
That proves she was the woman in the sarcophagus, doesn't it ?
证明她是女人 在石棺中，不是吗？
It's possible. Where did you find this ?
这是可能的。 您在哪里找到的？
In the laundry room. We wore gloves, for the fingerprints.
在洗衣房里。我们穿了 手套，用于指纹。
You have done well.
你做得很好。
Remember to relax your fingers.
记住要放松手指。
You need to press the tip of your finger, but not so it hurts.
您需要按一下 手指，但不会那么痛。
Monsieur Snowshoe...
先生雪靴...
Softly.
轻轻的。
Without touching the other fingers.
不碰 其他手指。
I have come to see your sister, but first I have a question..
我来看你姐姐 但首先我有一个问题。
..to ask madam.
..问夫人。
I am in the way.
我在路上
But we'll resume later. You have real potential.
但是我们稍后再继续。 你有真正的潜力。
Don't look so disapproving.
看起来不要这么反对。
I have the right to learn the guitar, even with a nice man.
我有权学习吉他，即使是一个好男人。 伪造的杰作， 我给你戴顶帽子！ 但是情况已经 如此复杂。
I have never seen this envelope, where did you find it ?
我没看过这个信封 你在哪里找到它 ？
You didn't write this ? - But, no.
你没有写这个吗？ - 但不是。
I don't understand.
我不明白
Do you recognise this envelope ?
你认得 这个信封？
Yes. It's the letter that I sent.
是。 这是我发的信。
You have found Martina ?
您已经找到Martina吗？
This envelope was found here.
在这里找到这个信封。
You think the woman in the sarcophagus really is.. Martina ?
你以为那个女人 石棺真的是..玛蒂娜？
It seems probable.
似乎有可能。
It looks as if you are leaving us.
好像你是 离开我们。
Are your interrogations finished ?
你的讯问 完成了吗？
Yes. For the moment.
是。暂时。
He has found out something, that one.
他发现了一些东西， 那个。
What was he sniffing around for ?
他在嗅什么 为？
Why tell him about Martina ?
为什么向他介绍马丁娜（Martina）？
Yes. Washing our dirty linen like that.
是。洗脏的亚麻布 像那样。
You should be thanking me, actually.
你应该感谢我 其实。
And why ?
又为什么呢？
The police would find it suspicious if no-one spoke..
警察会找到它 如果没有人讲话，则很可疑。
..now the dead woman seems really to be Martina.
..现在死去的女人似乎 真的是马丁娜。 885年
What now ?
现在怎么办 ？
The installation is antiquated.
安装陈旧。
I would never have thought it of you.
我永远都不会想 它的你。
You are trying to ruin me ?
你想毁了我吗？
Reassure yourself, M. Charpentier, it will cost you almost nothing.
让自己放心，夏彭捷先生， 它几乎不会花你什么。
What do you call ''nothing'' ? Name the price ! Name it !
您称什么为“无”？ 命名价格！命名吧！
Is that true ?!
真的吗 ？！
You're not saying it just to soft-soap me ?
你不是在说 软肥皂给我？
I swear it. On a cross of wood, a cross of iron.
我发誓。在十字架上 木头，铁十字架。
Oh ! How did you do it ?
喔！你是怎么做到的 ？
You are an angel, a pearl !
你是天使，珍珠！
A fairy ! - Oh !
童话 ！ -哦！
Oh ! Please !
喔！请 ！
You smell of good garlic ! What a woman !
你闻到大蒜的香气！ 真是个女人！
What a waist ! What hips ! What a chest !
好腰！什么臀部！ 真胸！
Mme. Beresford,...
嗯贝雷斯福德，...
This evening, you will dine with us.
今天晚上 你会和我们一起吃饭。
It's gone again !
它又消失了！
You will sit next to me.
你会坐在我旁边。
You do not look or act like a domestic, Mme. Beresford.
你看起来或行为不像 国内，女士贝雷斯福德。
Who are you ? Where do you come from ?
你是谁 ？ 你从哪里来的 ？
You discover a dead body on your arrival..
你发现尸体 在您抵达时
and the police hold us.
警察抱住了我们
< I have been watching you closely.
<我一直在看 你亲密。
And I will continue to do so.
我将继续这样做。
But what were you doing there ?
但是你在那里做什么？
I wanted to surprise you, and it went wrong.
我想给你一个惊喜 它出了错。
Give me some light.
给我一点光。
Yes. Wait a bit.
是。稍等一会。
I didn't want to miss our Christmas tradition.
我不想错过 我们的圣诞节传统。
I have hurt you !
我伤害了你！
Where is it, the champagne ? Ah !
香槟在哪里？ 啊！
Colonel Beresford ! Mm...
贝雷斯福德上校！ 嗯...
Some facts don't hold together.
有些事实不能统一起来。
What's that, Prudence ?
那是什么，Prudence？
1, the envelope addressed to Martina was found here.
1，信封寄给 在这里找到了玛蒂娜。
2, the Martina we found was about 20 years old.
2，我们发现的玛蒂娜酒是 大约20岁。
And 3, the body has the feet of a dancer.
3，身体有 舞者的脚。
And our dancer is in the West Indies with her Englishman.
我们的舞者在西方 印度人和她的英国人。
We were given a false clue, and we ran with it !
我们得到了一个错误的线索， 然后我们就跑了！
< Mademoiselle Prudence !
<小姐谨慎！
Yes, I'm coming, I'm coming !
是的，我要来了，我要来了！
Merry Christmas, my dear.
圣诞快乐，亲爱的。
Give big hugs to the little ones for me.
给予小小的拥抱 给我的。
Will you do me up ?
你愿意帮我吗？
Thank you. How do I look ?
谢谢。 我看起来怎么样 ？
Now you can creep out as secretly as you came in.
现在，您可以像 当你进来时偷偷地
The jewel suits you so well, my dear Mme. Beresford.
宝石非常适合您， 我亲爱的女士。贝雷斯福德。
Dear Mme. Beresford. - Oh, not again !
亲爱的女士贝雷斯福德。 -哦，不再了！
It looks like Mother's brooch.
看起来像母亲的胸针。
You're right, actually.
你说得对，实际上。
It does resemble it, yes.
它确实很像，是的。 937年
I wonder !
我想知道 ！
Excuse me.
劳驾。
Excuse me. An urgent case, I must leave you.
劳驾。紧急情况 我必须离开你。
A shame, I will accompany you. - Thank you.
真可惜，我会陪你的。 - 谢谢。
This is good, the soup.
这很好，汤。
Ah, main course ! The capon !...
啊，主菜！ 围裙！...
Are your suitcases ready ? Not the pyjamas yet.
你的手提箱准备好了吗？ 还没有睡衣。
What time is your mother getting here tomorrow ?
你妈妈几点钟 明天到这里吗？
At ten o'clock.
在十点整。
<I'm so excited to be going skiing at Sils Maria !
<我很高兴能去 在Sils Maria滑雪！
< Oh, what a mess !
<哦，真是一团糟！
< I will miss you, Mme. Poppins.
<我会想念你的，女士。罂粟花。
< Will you go there for your holiday ?
<你会去那儿吗 你的假期？
What is wrong, Valerie ? - I don't know.
瓦莱丽（Valerie）有什么问题？ - 我不知道。
Where do you feel bad ? - In my stomach.
您在哪里感到难过？ -在我的肚子里。
It doesn't feel right.
感觉不对。
What is happening ?
怎么了 ？
Go and lay down.
去躺下
What is this ? I will get help.
这是什么 ？ 我会得到帮助。
I am sick !
我病了 ！ 957年
Lay down, I'll be back.
躺下，我会回来的。
Mlle. Charpentier,..
嗯Charpentier ..
..the little ones are sick.
..小孩子生病了。
Are you not well ? No.
你不舒服吗 没有。
I... I'll be back.
我...我会回来的
They are all out of trouble. We must identify what happened.
他们都摆脱了麻烦。 我们必须确定发生了什么。
You are the only one unaffected. Did you eat everything ?
您是唯一一个不受影响的人。 都吃了吗
Yes, apart from the Yule log, I've never liked it.
是的，除了Yule原木之外， 我从来不喜欢它。
I didn't drink any of the champagne.
我没喝酒 任何香槟。
Is there anything left ?
还有什么吗？
No, they left nothing. They even sucked the bones.
不，他们什么也没留下。 他们甚至吮吸骨头。
Apart from the candied fruits and the carcase of the capon,..
除了蜜饯 和cap子的尸体，..
..there is nothing left. I also washed the dishes.
..没有什么剩下。 我也洗碗了。
My God ! Do you think it's arsenic ?
天哪 ！ 你认为这是砷吗？
How do you know ?
你怎么知道的 ？
Yes, there's a good chance that it is.
是的，很有机会 这是。
The killer may be among them, pretending to be sick.
杀手可能在其中 假装生病。
Could you tell the difference between true sickness and fake ?
你能告诉我区别吗 真正的病假之间？
I don't think so, no.
我不这样认为，不。
I'll call for a nurse. She should be here by 8 o'clock.
我叫护士。她 应该在八点钟到这里。
I will prepare something for each of them.
我会为 他们每个人。
I will be back to see how they are.
我会回来的 看看他们怎么样。
While I'm away, keep your eyes open.
我不在的时候 睁大你的眼睛。
Especially on Emma. - Yes, count on me.
尤其是艾玛。 -是的，请指望我。
I never thought I'd have to work on Christmas Day !
我从来没有想过我必须 在圣诞节那天工作！
It's Mlle. Emma I feel sorry for.
是Mlle。艾玛 我很抱歉。
I said to Mme. Beresford that the lobsters were worthless.
我对夫人说贝雷斯福德那个 龙虾一文不值。
But she replied : ''No, the lobsters are very fresh.''
但是她回答:“不， 龙虾很新鲜。''
Who can say, with all the pollutants thrown in the sea.
谁能说 污染物被扔到海里。
In any case, I wouldn't eat them.
在任何情况下， 我不会吃的
All of them could have been taken.
他们全部 本来可以。
I am Mme. Valois, the mother of Valerie.
我是女士瓦卢瓦 瓦莱丽的母亲。
You've come to collect her ?
你来找她吗？
I wouldn't let your daughter come here any more.
我不会让你的女儿 再来这里。
Mme. Valois, I will take you to Valerie.
嗯瓦卢瓦，我带你 到瓦莱丽。
The house has suffered from a bout of food poisoning..
这房子遭受了 一顿食物中毒..
..but Valerie is doing well.
..但Valerie表现不错。
Both she and Alexie are ready to leave. Follow me.
她和阿历克斯都准备好了 离开。跟着我。
Ah ! My little girl !
啊！我的小女孩！
What happened to you ?
你怎么了 ？
I must tell you. Alexie's papa had a brother..
我必须告诉你。阿列克谢的 爸爸有一个兄弟
..who is dead, and his wife...
..谁死了， 和他的妻子
Get Emma to send the nurse away, her charges will ruin me !
让艾玛（Emma）送走护士， 她的指控会毁了我！
That would mean I would have to take care of you myself.
那意味着我会 照顾自己
And I cannot be everywhere at the same time.
我无处不在 与此同时。
Why can't Emma help you ?
艾玛为什么不能帮助您？
She is confined to her bed.
她被限制在床上。
And the others ? - The same.
还有其他？ - 相同。
But they are all doing well. They are resting.
但是他们都做得很好。 他们正在休息。
What is that ? - Some bouillon and biscuits.
那是什么 ？ -一些肉汤和饼干。
Take it away. I want meat.
把它拿开。我要肉。
The doctor has forbidden that for the moment.
医生禁止 此刻。
The doctor is an ass, I am well. Bring me meat !
医生是个屁，我很好。 把肉给我！
May I see Alexie's father ?
我可以看看阿列克谢的父亲吗？
Unfortunately, he is sick...
不幸， 他病了...
My daughter told me about the woman in the sarcophagus.
我女儿告诉我有关 石棺的女人。
I have to speak to someone in the family.
我必须跟某人说话 在家庭中。
I will ask Mlle. Emma.
我会问Mlle。艾玛
Tell her that it's about Martina Petrovna.
告诉她那是关于 玛蒂娜（Martina Petrovna）。
Martina Petrovna ?
马丁娜·彼得罗夫娜（Martina Petrovna）？
You have heard of Martina ?
您听说过玛蒂娜吗？
It's likely she is the woman found in the sarcophagus.
她可能是女人 在石棺中发现。
That just isn't possible. - How so ?
那是不可能的。 - 为何如此 ？
Because I am Martina Petrovna.
因为我是Martina Petrovna。
I met Edmond in Damascus.
我在大马士革遇到了埃德蒙。
We were together for a while, But then came the split-up.
我们在一起有一段时间了 但是后来分裂了。
I was sent to Belgrade.
我被送到贝尔格莱德。
There I met Valerie's father, who was posted down there.
在那里我遇到了瓦莱丽的父亲， 谁被张贴在那里。
A Frenchman, like Edmond.
法国人，例如埃德蒙。
You know...
你懂...
I have never forgotten your brother, and...
我从来没有忘记你 兄弟，还有...
When I learnt that, at boarding school,..
当我得知 在寄宿学校，..
..my daughter had become friends with your niece,..
我女儿已经成为 你侄女的朋友，..
..you cannot know how much I was moved by this coincidence.
..你不知道我有多少 被这个巧合感动了。
I even thought of writing to you.
我什至想到写信给你。
And then, I said to myself, what good to stir up the past ?
然后，我对自己说: 激发过去有什么好处？
But when my daughter told me about the body found here,..
但是当我女儿告诉我 关于这里发现的尸体，..
..I wanted to warn you. - Thank you so much.
..我想警告你。 - 非常感谢。
She is so charming.
她是如此迷人。
So, who was it wrote to me using her name ?
那是谁给我写的 用她的名字吗？
Some crook, who then backed away from his deception.
一些骗子，然后谁支持 远离他的欺骗。
What is it, Mme. Beresford ?
它是什么， 嗯贝雷斯福德？
It is.. your brother, Augustin.
是..你的兄弟奥古斯丁。
What about Augustin ? I thought his condition...
那奥古斯丁呢？ 我以为他的状况
My brother is dead,..
我哥哥死了..
..do I read you right ?
..我读对了吗？
I thought he was stronger. Clearly I was wrong.
我以为他更坚强。 显然我错了。
You don't seem very upset.
你似乎并不难过。
Tears for the dead, no thank you !
死者的眼泪 不，谢谢 ！
You are much too sentimental. You could become irksome.
你太感伤了。 你可能会变得讨厌。
What's this I hear ? Augustin has breathed his last ?
我听到什么？ 奥古斯丁已经呼吸了他的最后一口？
M. Charpentier, please return to your bed.
M. Charpentier， 请回到你的床上。
No need, I have never felt better.
没必要， 我从来没有感觉好过。
So, is it true ? Is he really dead ?
那么，是真的吗？ 他真的死了吗？
The one who was the most anxious to inherit.
最厉害的那个 渴望继承。
So much for the artist ! One down, two to go !
对于艺术家来说，是如此的多！ 一下来，二去！
How can you say that ?
你怎么能这么说呢 ？
Just you see, I will bury them all !
你看 我将它们全部埋葬！
Misfortune never comes alone.
不幸永远不会孤单。
Now I can speak out, and tell you about these beauties !
现在我可以说出来了 告诉你这些美女！
Do you want to hear ? - No.
你想听吗？ -不
What is this ? Are you smoking, now ?
这是什么 ？ 你现在在抽烟吗？
These people, Belisaire, they are like wolves.
这些人，比利时人， 他们就像狼。
No, not wolves, jackals.
不，不是狼， 狼。
Sorry to hear of your brother. - Alright.
很抱歉听到你的兄弟。 - 好的。
Madame is home ? - She is waiting for you.
夫人在家吗 -她在等你。
< God ! Camembert and everything ?
<上帝！ 卡门培尔奶酪和一切？
Raphael, you look utterly dreadful !
拉斐尔 你看起来简直可怕！
You... look resplendent. Been out amusing yourself ?
你...真好 出去逗自己吗？
Absolutely everyone is in Mauritius now. God !
绝对每个人都在 现在的毛里求斯。天哪！
But you've already spent a month there.
但是你已经花了 一个月。
Surely not ? A whole month ? - Yes.
当然不是吗？一个月？ -是的
Oh well, as you say ! God !
哦，正如您所说！ 天哪！
And money is rather tight, for the present at least.
钱很紧， 至少目前。
In New York, I fell in with this crazy woman called Hermeline.
在纽约，我迷上了 这个疯狂的女人叫Hermeline。
She told the entire table that they had found..
她告诉整张桌子 他们发现了..
..the body of a woman at Vallée-aux-Loups,...
..女人的身体 Vallée-aux-Loups，...
It was just so embarrassing.
太尴尬了。
But it is true.
但这是真的。
Really! Who was she, this woman ?
真！ 她是谁，这个女人？
A woman from the East, apparently.
来自东方的女人 显然。
A woman from the East !
来自东方的女人！
God ! I don't feel so good.
天哪！ 我感觉不太好。
It won't keep me from my bed.
这不会让我离开床。
Me too. I am completely jet-lagged.
我也是。 我完全处于落后状态。
I almost forgot...
我差点忘了...
This is for you.
这个给你。
You have brought me back a gift ?
你带我回来 一个礼物 ？
No, it arrived this afternoon by Chronopost.
不，今天下午到了 由Chronopost。
''Continue the treatment for three days.
''继续治疗 三天。
''Two tablets in the evening before bed.''
晚上两片 睡前。''
Lagarde told me to stop. - You must have misunderstood.
拉加德叫我停下来。 -您一定有误会。
In any case, it can't do you any harm.
在任何情况下， 它不会对您造成任何伤害。
You're right, it can't do any harm.
你是对的， 它不会造成任何伤害。
Raphael, God, I'm freezing !
拉斐尔，天哪，我在冻结！
I suspected Augustin, and he is dead.
我怀疑奥古斯丁， 他死了
I suspected Raphael,
我怀疑拉斐尔
I dare not say I suspect Frederic, it might kill him.
我不敢说我​​怀疑 弗雷德里克，这可能会杀死他。
As for Emma...
至于艾玛...
No, let's get back on the track of the dancer.
不，让我们回到 舞者的踪迹。
From the start of this case,..
从这种情况开始
..we concentrated on Martina Charpentier,..
..我们专注于 玛蒂娜·夏蓬蒂尔
..because of the faked letter we were shown,..
..因为假信件 我们被展示了..
..let's admit it, with heads bowed in shame.
..让我们承认 头低下头。
We must find the identity of this Anna Karenine.
我们必须找到身份 这个安娜·卡列宁（Anna Karenine）。
I believe that will lead us to the killer.
我相信那会带领我们 给杀手
The murder is linked to the Charpentier family..
谋杀与 夏朋蒂家族
..but not in the way we've considered so far.
..但不妨碍 到目前为止，我们已经考虑过。
Don't you think so ?
你不这样认为吗？
I understood nothing that you said.
我什么都不懂 你说的
Ah well. Me, I have a plan.
呃，好吧。我，我有一个计划。
Yes sir, I have a plan.
是的，先生，我有一个计划。
But I don't think I'll tell you what it is.
但我不认为我会告诉 你是什​​么。
Well, okay. It involves Aunt Babette.
哦，那好吧。 它涉及巴贝特姨妈。
With Aunt Babette ? - Yes, with her.
和巴贝特姨妈在一起？ -是的，和她在一起。
< This is the limit !
<这是极限！
First, you don't believe me, and take me for mad.
首先，你不相信我， 让我生气
Now, you ask me to do something embarrassing.
现在，你要我做 令人尴尬的事情。
Why should I go and take tea with strangers, and..
我为什么要去喝茶 和陌生人在一起，和..
..then pretend to feel ill ?
..然后假装感到不适？
I tell you, I don't like it !
我告诉你，我不喜欢它！
I detest this sort of joke.
我讨厌这种玩笑。
This is not about comedy, but about murder.
这不是关于喜剧， 但是关于谋杀
Prudence just asks you to follow her instructions.
谨慎只要求您 按照她的指示。
Aunt Babette ! No !
巴贝特姨妈！ 不行
Well then, if I've understood her instructions,..
那好吧，如果我了解了 她的指示..
..I engage in a pleasant conversation with these toffs...
..我从事愉快 与这些太太的对话...
And suddenly...
突然...
Suddenly, I have a small problem.
突然， 我有一个小问题。
I use some pretext, er, I'll invent something,..
我用一些借口，呃， 我会发明一些东西..
..in order to leave the room.
..为了离开房间。
And then ? - You return to the room.
然后 ？ -你回到房间。
I return, when ? - At the signal.
我什么时候回来？ -在信号。
Ah, there'll be a signal ? - Mm...
啊，会有信号吗？ -嗯...
And I can show them my Zigoeunus ?
我可以给他们看 我的Zigoeunus？
''Zigoeunus Thomasus moth,
''Zigoeunus Thomasus蛾，
''..North Sinnamary, French Guiana, 28 December 2007''
''..North Sinnamary，法文 圭亚那，2007年12月28日''
It is a male. Beautiful, isn't he ?
是男的 美丽，不是吗？
It is the highlight of my entire career.
这是亮点 我整个职业生涯
The male lives only for a few hours.
男性只活着 几个小时。
Immediately after having ''met'' the female,..
拥有后立即 “满足”女性，..
..he dies.
..他死了。
That is why he is so rare and difficult to capture.
这就是为什么他如此稀有 而且很难捕获。
But there are several techniques : the picket line,..
但是有几个 技术:纠察线，..
..the zigzag chase.
..之字形追逐。
Keep it up.
保持。
They are capricious creatures, sensitive to fragrances :..
他们是反复无常的生物 对香水敏感:..
..the patchouli, the honeysuckle...
..广patch香， 金银花...
Chanel number 5...
香奈儿5号...
The most important thing for the catch is for the hunter..
最重要的是 渔获物是给猎人的。
..to conceal his shadow.
..隐瞒他的影子。
But I am talking too much...
但是我讲的太多了...
And I'm not telling you what a wonderful home you have !
我没有告诉你什么 您拥有一个美好的家！
Something for now.
现在有事。
Oh, how delicious ! Red mullet on toast.
哦，真好吃！ 在多士的红鱼。
Quite a change to your diet in the Amazon !
改变饮食 在亚马逊！
You might say so !
您可能会这样说！
But, that said, ants in pate are not so bad.
但是，这就是蚂蚁的头脑 还不错
They crack pleasantly on the tooth.
他们愉快地破裂 在牙齿上。
And it's very economic.
而且非常经济。
Do you have the recipe ?
你有食谱吗？
Now.
现在。
Mm ! This is delicious.
嗯！这个好吃。
Would you like some fresh air ? - On the contrary.
您想要新鲜的空气吗？ - 反之。
You look very pale !
你看起来很苍白！
I am sorry. I must excuse myself for a few moments.
对不起。我必须原谅 我自己片刻。
Where is it ?
它在哪里 ？
Through there.
通过那里。
Thank you, Francois, for coming.
谢谢弗朗索瓦， 来。
You look much better. You have got back..
你看起来好多了。 你回来了..
..some of your colour.
..您的一些颜色。
What is wrong here ?
这是怎么了？
Stay calm. - Blockage in my throat !
保持冷静。 -阻塞我的喉咙！
Let me take a look. Open your mouth.
让我看一看。 张开嘴。
Calm yourself. Turn towards me.
你冷静一下。 转向我。
Tilt your head.
倾斜你的头。
It's him !
是他 ！
The man on the train !
火车上的男人！
No, no. Say nothing more.
不，不。 别说了。
You didn't think..
你没想到
..that a witness saw you strangle that woman.
目击者看见你 勒死那个女人。
My aunt, Babette Boutiti, saw you.
我的姑姑Babette Boutiti， 见到你。
She was on the train..
她在火车上。
..that ran beside your own.
..那在你自己旁边跑。
Suddenly, she saw...
突然，她看到了...
Mme. Beresford, I know you have been..
嗯贝雷斯福德， 我知道你去过
..overworked recently, but now,..
..最近工作过度， 但现在，..
..you must be delirious. - No, not at all !
..你一定要精神错乱。 - 一点都不 ！
Why would I strangle a woman unknown to me ?
我为什么要angle死一个女人 我不知道吗？
Unknown ?
不明？
This woman, on the contrary,..
相反，这个女人
..you knew very well.
..你非常了解。
She was your wife.
她是你的妻子。
He wanted to marry you, but he was already married..
他想嫁给你 但是他已经结婚了
..to Anna Stravinska, known as Anna Karenine.
..致安娜·斯特拉文斯卡（Anna Stravinska） 作为安娜·卡列宁（Anna Karenine）。
A dancer who refused him a divorce.
一名舞者 谁拒绝了他离婚
I thought he was a widower.
我以为他是个ower夫。
And I thought you were a widow.
我想 你是寡妇
Not a widow, not a domestic, not a cook.
不是寡妇，不是家政， 不是厨师
And this is my last service.
这是我最后的服务。
Emma, you talked to him about Edmond ?
艾玛，你跟他谈过 埃德蒙？
And that was when he got an idea.
那时是 他有个主意。
He wrote to you a letter, and signed it ''Martina'',..
他给你写了一封信， 并签署了“马丁娜”
..killed his wife, and hid the body in the sarcophagus,..
..杀死了他的妻子，并隐藏了 石棺中的身体..
..and, thanks to that letter, we were led astray,..
..而且，由于那封信， 我们被误入歧途，..
..and the body was identified as that of Martina.
..身体被识别 和马丁娜一样。
< And so, the family was implicated in the murder,..
<因此，一家人 与谋杀有牵连，..
..while he prepared for his next step.
..他准备 他的下一步。
< He planned to kill all your brothers, and incriminate..
<他计划杀死你所有的人 兄弟，并入罪。
..the one who remained :..
..剩下的那个人...
..your father.
..你的父亲。
So that you would be very rich by the time he married you.
这样你会很富有 等他嫁给你的时候
If it had been me who died on Christmas night, his plan..
如果是我死了 圣诞之夜，他的计划。
..would have fallen apart. But I was too strong.
..会崩溃了。 但是我太坚强了。
He gave you a small dose of arsenic.
他给了你一点剂量 砷。
Just enough to give you stomach pains.
足以给你 胃痛。
< The next day, the nurse, without knowing it,..
<第二天，护士， 不知道，..
..gave Augustin the fatal dosage prepared by the doctor.
..让奥古斯丁致命 剂量由医生准备。
Then it was only necessary to send Raphael his dosage..
那就只需要 寄给拉斐尔剂量
What a bastard ! -< You should thank him !
真是个混蛋！ -<您应该感谢他！
You owe him a debt of gratitude.
你欠他感激之情。
All he brought me was trouble.
他带给我的只是麻烦。
A sarcophagus in pieces...
一块石棺...
And all the rest !
还有其余的！
You, your fortune has frankly doubled !
你，你的财富有 坦白说加倍！
They love their money, this family.
他们爱他们的钱， 这个家庭。
I have avoided Christmas with the family !
我避免过圣诞节 跟家人在一起 ！
They are they still here.
他们还在他们这里。
They said they were leaving !
他们说他们要走了！
Perhaps they decided to stay for New Year's.
也许他们决定留下来 新年
Are there now ten of them ?
现在有十个吗？
No, just the two.
不，只有两个。
And two can make this row ?
还有两个可以进入这一行？
Aunt Babette doesn't know how lucky she is.
巴贝特姨妈不知道 她有多幸运。
Nothing but butterflies, while living in a tent.
只是蝴蝶 住在帐篷里
Camping in the wild !
在野外露营！
I am parched !
我干了！
Belisaire, wake up.
Belisaire，醒。
Open your eyes.
张开你的眼睛。
And tell me what you see.
告诉我你所看到的。
Millions and millions of stars.
数百万 星。
And what do you make of them ?
您如何看待它们？
That there are millions of galaxies..
那有几百万 星系..
..and billions of planets.
以及数十亿个行星。
That Saturn is part of Leo.
土星是狮子座的一部分。
That the time is approximately..
时间到了 大约..
..a quarter past three.
..三点一刻。
That it should be a nice day tomorrow.
那应该是美好的一天 明天。
I see that God is all-powerful..
我看到上帝是 无所不能..
..and that we are small and insignificant in the Universe.
..而我们很小 在宇宙中微不足道。
And you, Prudence, what do you see ?
还有你，Prudence， 你看到了什么 ？
My poor Belisaire, I see you are a proper nitwit !
我可怜的Belisaire，我明白了 你是一个适当的机智者！
Me, I see that we are finally free.
我， 我看到我们终于有空了。
English subtitles : David Blake (2015)
英文字幕 : 大卫·布雷克（2015）